《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
ADAMA: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
你杀我  我下载到新躯壳  我回来  我们重新开始
You kill me, I download, I come back, we start over.
你会挽着我的肩膀
You're gonna hold me in your arms.
你会和我说你爱我
You're gonna tell me that you love me.
我不属于这里  让我走
I don't belong here! Let me out!
你从哪得到这些消息的  谁是你的线人?
Where are you getting this stuff? Who's your source?
我不知道
I have no idea.
线人不愿意暴露他们的身份
The source won't tell me what their name is.
或许对我们更安全
It's probably safer for all of us.
总统先生?    早上好 盖塔
Mr. President? Good morning, Gaeta.
是殖民地的信号  识别码吻合
It's a Colonial transmission. The recognition codes match.
对 我们和地面取得了联系
Oh, yeah, we've got a link to the ground.
我们收到个信号
TYROL: We've got a signal.
说什么?    坚持住 我们来接你们了
What's it say? "Have hope. We're coming for you. "
我们联系上了!
RACETRACK: We made contact!
泰上校成立了抵抗组织反抗赛昂人
Colonel Tigh has formed an insurgent group against the Cylons,
现在他们已经准备好等待指示…
and now they're ready and waiting for instructions
来协调救援行动
on how to coordinate the rescue effort.
会好起来的
It's gonna be okay.
谁是我们的下一个目标
TIGH: What's our next target?
这是今天拿到的
TYROL: I got these today.
是新卡布里卡警察学校
They're security plans for the graduation ceremony
毕业典礼的安保计划
of the New Caprica Police Academy.
最乐观估计 警察人数在200左右
Our best guess puts the total police force at around 200.
我甚至无法相信哪怕只有20个人
ROSLIN: I wouldn't have believed there'd be 20 people
会背叛自己的同胞
who would turn against their own kind.
我不喜欢这样 上校 我们越限了
I don't like this one, Colonel. I think we're the ones crossing the line here.
他是个战士  军士长
He's a soldier, Chief.
这不是我们第一次把战士派上有去无回的战场中了
Not the first time we've sent a soldier on a one-way mission.
放话出去 谁替赛昂人卖命 就是我们的目标
TIGH: Send a message. You work with the Cylons, you're a target.
赛昂人可不加什么区分  我们也没有
No boundaries for the Cylons, there's no boundaries for us!
我们围捕那些反叛者的领袖 然后公开处死他们
We round up the leaders of the insurgency and we execute them publicly.
发个消息说刽子手来了
Send a message that the gloves are coming off.
现在  所有重要人物都被拘禁起来了
Everyone of importance is being looked at right now.
你也不能幸免
You're no exception.
我能帮助你  劳拉
I can help you, Laura,
但我却帮不了我自己
in ways I cannot help myself.
我能保护你
I can protect you,
但是你必须明白  形势已经改变
but you have to understand the situation has changed now.
抵抗活动已经出格了
The insurgency has crossed the line.
自杀式爆炸袭击
Suicide bombings.
这太可恶了
It's abhorrent.
这与我们所信仰的向背而弛
It's contrary to everything that we believe in.
所以你...
So you...
你和我  我们将...
You and I, we will...
我们将要公开谴责这样的行动
We will publicly condemn these tactics.
它们不能被合法化  以任何形式
They cannot be legitimized in any shape or form.
这样的行动毕竟让赛昂人感到了恐惧
There is something that scares the Cylons after all.
人体炸弹应该使我们全都感到恐惧
I should think using men and women as human bombs should scare us all.
绝望的人们采取绝望的做法
Desperate people take desperate measures.
好吧  看着我的眼睛
All right, look me in the eye.
注视我的眼睛  并告诉我你赞成
Look me in the eye and tell me that you approve
让年轻的男女胸口绑着炸弹
of sending young men and women into crowded places
走进喧闹的人群
with explosives strapped to their chests.
我等着你注视我的眼睛并说你赞成这么做
I'm waiting for you to look me in the eye and tell me that you approve!
33人被杀死了
Thirty-three people killed,
而他们的过错不过是穿上了警察制服
and their only crime was putting on a police uniform,
只不过是想给混乱的地区带来秩序    秩序?
trying to bring some order to the chaos out there. Order?
通过在深夜里逮捕无辜的人
By arresting innocent people in the dead of night,
没有任何审判就无限期地扣留他们 折磨他们
detaining them indefinitely without charge, torturing them...
等等 没人受到折磨    ...为了获取情报
Now wait a minute. Nobody's been tortured! ... for information!
这话去跟泰上校说吧
Tell that to Colonel Tigh.
没人受到折磨
Nobody has been tortured.
我们打住吧
We're done here.
我希望你理解眼下形势严峻
I hope you understand the severity of the situation
我请求你顺从你的良心
and ask you to obey the dictates of your conscience,
那也是我一直在做的
which is what I've always done.
对此  我毫不怀疑
Of that I have no doubt.
请把这位可爱女士的鞋还给她
Please give this lovely lady her shoes back,
然后让她离开这里
then get her out of here.
戒严现在生效
MAN ON PA: Curfew is now in effect.
在街道上的任何人都将受到严厉惩罚
There should be no people on the street without clearance.
戒严现在生效
Curfew is now in effect.
在街道上的任何人都将受到严厉惩罚
There should be no people on the street without clearance.
你明白给你的命令了吗  队长?  一切都清楚吗?
Do you understand your orders, Captain? Everything clear?
是的  长官        很好
Yes, sir. Good.
不要担心  我们会在后面支援你们
Don't worry, we have your back.
你听说了吗?  赛昂人削减了食物配给
Did you hear? The Cylons cut food rations today.
我们听说了
We heard.
与猛禽下一次联络的时间还剩多少?
How long before the next Raptor transmission?
两分钟
Two minutes.
他们想要关闭市场
Yeah, they're talking about shutting down the marketplace.
认为那里有安全隐患
It's a security risk.
我们会换个目标
We'll shift targets.
你原本要袭击市场?
You were gonna hit the marketplace.
市场  那里全是平民
The market, full of civilians.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
我们要搞清楚我们站在哪一边
You know, we need to figure out whose side we're on.
我们站在哪一边?
Which side are we on?
我们站在魔鬼这边  军士长
We're on the side of the demons, Chief.
我们是天国花园里的邪恶之人  被死亡的力量驱使着
We're evil men in the gardens of paradise, sent by the forces of death
无论我们到哪里  都传播破坏与毁灭
to spread devastation and destruction wherever we go.
我很惊讶你连这都不知道
I'm surprised you didn't know that.
联系上了
TYROL: Contact.
他们准备好接收情报了
Get ready for the sitrep.
发送两次  保险起见
Send it twice, just to make sure.
这是需要逮捕并送往监狱的那些人的名单
CAVIL: Here are the names of those to be arrested and sent to detention.
我...
I...
其中一些人我认识
I know some of these people.
我确信你认识他们
I'm sure you do.
他们都是抵抗份子  杰米  我们必须打破暴力循环
They're all insurgents, Jammer. We have to break the cycle of violence.
好了  整装出发
Okay, suit up.
不久你们就不必再戴这个了
You won't have to wear those much longer.
最终人们将把你们视为英雄
Eventually, your people will see you as heroes.
但不是今晚
Not tonight.
5号至10号 他们在右边的帐篷
JAMMER: Take numbers five through 10. They're gonna be in tents to the right.
按名单顺序抓
Follow down to the end.
其余的人维护现场  明白了吗?
The rest of you guys have got to keep quiet, okay?
我们是新卡布里卡警察
MAN: This is the New Caprica Police!
你因参与暴乱而被逮捕了
You are under arrest for colluding with the insurgency!
别动 你被逮捕了
Don't move! You're under arrest!
你被逮捕了
You are under arrest.
这是NCP的突袭行动(NCP 新卡布里卡警察)
This is an NCP raid! Get your hands up!
凯莉 过来    不 不
Cally, come here! No! No!
这是NCP的突袭行动 举起手来    放开我 不
This is an NCP raid. Get your hands up. Let go of me! No!
我的孩子!不!放开我!
My baby! No! No, let go of me!
不!
No!
嘿!别哭  别哭
Hey, no, no, no, no.
我在这  我在这  好了  别哭
I got you, I got you. Yeah, yeah, yeah. There you go.
妈妈会回来的  她会没事的
Mommy's coming back. It's okay. It's okay.
他们的人数少了一点
Their numbers are a little thin.
这上面说  泰上校有1150名武装人员
It says here Tigh commands 1,150 armed effectives.
他们的人是少了一点
That's a lot less than he should have
就算加上前舰队的全部军官以及那里能召集到的所有人员...
if you count all former Fleet officers and enlisted available down there.
可能已经遭到重创了
He could be taking heavy losses.
他们提及了赛昂人的镇压
They mentioned a Cylon crackdown.
我们应该把抵抗组织中可用的机师解救出来
We should get a breakdown of available pilots in the insurgent group.
如果我们要做成这件事
Somebody's gotta fly those ships off the ground
就得有人去驾驶地面上的那些飞船
if we're gonna pull this off.
那些飞船哪也去不了
Those ships aren't going anywhere yet.
赛昂人已经把着陆的殖民飞船上的启动钥匙转移了
"The Cylons have removed launch keys from grounded colonial ships.
地点未知  泰罗尔说的
"Location unknown. " It came from Tyrol.
我们可以作出新的启动钥匙吗?
Can we manufacture new launch keys?
别提了
APOLLO: Forget it.
启动钥匙的设计原理惊人的复杂
The specs on launch keys are incredibly sophisticated.
将花费数周去研制
It would take weeks just to do the R and D.
最好是少和地面上的人
The best option is for Saul and the people on the ground
能找到原来的启动钥匙
to find the original launch keys.
假如原来的钥匙被销毁了呢?
Assuming they weren't destroyed.
不可能
No. No way.
赛昂人会完好地保存它们
The Cylons would want to keep them safe,
以防他们有一天可能需要使用
just in case they need to use one of those ships someday.
她说得对 钥匙肯定还在某个地方
She's right. The keys gotta still be there somewhere.
我们可以向抵抗组织投放一些武器
We can make a weapons drop to the insurgents.
他们熟悉投放地形
They know the lay of the land,
他们打击赛昂人已经有数月之久了
they've been hitting the Cylons in the teeth for months.
假设他们有了工具  他们就能自己找到钥匙
Give them the tools. They can find the keys themselves.
不  不行
APOLLO: No. No way.
你过于乐观了
The only thing you've got going for you so far
赛昂人已经将防御区缩小到只有五艘基地之星那么大了
is that the Cylons reduced their defense perimeter to just five base ships.
你把重型武器投放下去 他们肯定会知道…
You put heavy weaponry down there, they're gonna know for sure
我们与地面上的人有联系
that we're in contact with the population.
就会有十艘基地之星上来  你的计划就完蛋了
They'll call in 10 more base ships, and then your whole plan is frakked.
有意思  我以为这是我们的计划  长官
Funny. I thought this was our plan, sir.
继续
Moving on,
军事计划一旦在手便会一直相随
the military plans you have in your hands are to be with you at all times.
他们为何把她抓了? 她什么事也没做
Why'd they pick her up? She hasn't done anything.
我们有一个孩子
We've got a baby, for Gods' sakes.
我不知道  我会努力查明原因
I don't know. I'll try to find out.
他们准备拘禁她多久?
How long are they gonna hold her?
拘留所由另一个部门掌管
The detention is run by a separate ministry.
他们没有给我们任何解释  为什么他们会抓...
They don't give us any reasons why they...
老天爷呀  菲里克斯
Gods damn it, Felix!
她什么事也没做  我们还有一个婴儿
She hasn't done anything. We've got a baby.
我知道  格伦  我很遗憾
I know, Galen. I'm sorry.
你怎么会这样?
How do you do it?
你为何会日复一日地帮助他们?
How do you help them day after day?
你将如何看待镜子中的自己?
How do you look yourself in the mirror?
我要去找我的儿子
I gotta get my son.
卡梅伦正看着他  但她还有自己的事情
Cameron's watching him, but she's got problems of her own.
军士长
Chief.
我会看看我能帮你什么忙 我会想办法找出原因的
I'll see what I can do. I'll see if there's something I can find out.
你为什么不尝试做些事情?
Why don't you try and do something?
你还好吗?  杰米  发生什么事了?
Hey, you okay? Jammer, what's going on?
我听说昨晚的事了 关于凯莉在那些名单上的事
I heard about last night. About Cally being on one of those lists.
我真的很遗憾
Yeah. I'm really sorry.
他妈的那些人类警察
Yeah. Frakking human police, huh?
如果你要问我  我说那是一群叛国贼
A bunch of traitors if you ask me.
那些参加警察的家伙
Some of those guys who joined up,
我希望他们的脑袋都开花  你知道吗?
I bet they're in over their heads, you know?
特别是让那些自杀炸弹...
Especially now with these suicide bombings.
起初他们认为他们是在做好事
At first, I bet you they thought they were doing something good, you know?
把赛昂人赶出街道 让我们自己维持治安
Get the Cylons off the streets, let us police our own.
他们是一群他妈的白痴
The police are frakking idiots.
他们想要什么?
What did they expect?
你知道那些家伙的名字吗?
You don't know any of those guys, do you? Any names?
名字? 完全不知道
Names? No. No, no idea.
该死
Damn.
凯莉怎样了? 为什么他们要把她抓起来?
What's up with Cally? Why did they put her in detention?
我不知道  她一件坏事都没干过
I don't know. She hasn't done a gods-damn thing.
我刚与盖塔聊过 他说他什么都不知道
I just talked to Gaeta. He says he doesn't know squat, or so he says.
盖塔是个好人  如果他知道什么...
Gaeta's a good guy. If he knows something...
他是该死的通敌者
He's a frakking collaborator.
你知道什么? 如果有一天这一切都结束了
You know what? One day, when this is all over,
类似盖塔这样的人都会被绞死
guys like Gaeta are gonna get strung up.
而像你我这样的人
Guys like you and me, we're gonna be there,
则是负责将绳子打结的人
tying the knots, making them tight.
真是一段丑陋的日子
LEOBEN: It's been a couple of ugly days.
我知道你不关心这个
I know you don't care about that,
可生命对于我们是有意义的
but life means something to us.
于是我决定向你展现生命是多么得珍贵
So I've decided to show you just how precious life can be,
即使在最艰难的日子里
how, even in the worst of times,
它也能让你恢复信念
it can restore your faith.
你还记得在卡布里卡的养殖场里的事吗?
Remember that breeding farm on Caprica?
我记得我把那地方给烧了
I remember I blew the frak out of the place.
但没有丧失所有东西
It wasn't a total loss.
我们抢救出一些东西
We were able to salvage certain things,
一些医学样本 例如你的卵巢
certain medical samples, like your ovary.
那是什么?
What's that?
这是凯西
This is Kacey.
凯西  这是卡拉 你的母亲
Kacey, this is Kara, your mother.
嗨
Hi.
不可思议
DUALLA: Unbelievable.
什么?
What?
上将决定派些人下到地面去
Admiral's decided to put some boots on the ground,
想要派一名军官下去
wants to send an officer as a liaison
充当我们与抵抗组织之间的联络人来协调援救行动
between us and the resistance elements on the planet to coordinate the rescue op.
很合理  有什么问题?
It makes sense. What's the problem?
派谁下去?
It's who he's sending.
他一定在开该死的玩笑  对不?
He's frakking kidding with this, right?
我也希望他是
I wish he were.
Hoshi先生  我要一驾猛禽5分钟内在机库甲板上准备完毕
Mr. Hoshi, I want a Raptor prepped and ready in five minutes on the hangar deck.
通知旗舰  我要登舰
Inform the flagship I'm coming aboard.
我要与上将开一个秘密会议
I want a private meeting with the Admiral.
是  长官
HOSHI: Aye, sir.
你想要干什么?
What are you gonna do?
干我很久都没干的事情
What I should have done a long time ago.
你不能这么做 她是赛昂人
You can't do this. She's a Cylon.
嗯  我相信她
Well, I trust her.
呃  这是个错误
Well, that's a mistake.
没错  那也是我的错误  对吧
Well, it'll be my mistake, won't it?
你在拿这艘船上所有人的生命去赌博
You are gambling with the lives of everyone on this ship.
还有我船上的每一个人
Everyone on my ship.
我不需要你来告诉我  什么是指挥官的责任
I don't need a lecture from you about the responsibilities of command.
我们的谈话结束了
We're done here.
我还没有说完 整个计划是一次不计后果的赌博
I'm not finished. This entire plan is a reckless gamble.
没错  你的确有权力让你指挥下的男男女女们去冒险
And yes, you certainly have the right to risk the lives of the men and women
但这不是重点
under your command, but that's not the issue.
重点是你在拿整个人类种族冒险
The issue is you are risking the lives of the entire human race.
我在试图拯救人类
I'm trying to save the human race.
不  不  你没在拯救
No. No, you're not.
你没有看到这一点  现在  整个人类种族?
That's what you're not seeing. Right now, the human race,
好吧  那里有2000个人挤在平民船上
well, that's the 2,000 people huddled in those civilian ships
当赛昂人回来时  他们设法离开了
that managed to get away when the Cylons came back.
他们才是保险箱
They're the safe bet.
他们才是我们应该守卫的人
They're the ones who survived and we should guard,
就像我们在他们攻击殖民地后所做的那样
just like we did after the attack on the colonies.
莎伦能渗透那些防御
Sharon can penetrate the Cylon defenses.
这不是她的问题
It's not about her.
赛昂百夫长无法从其他人形赛昂中分辨出她来
The Centurions can't distinguish her from the other humanoid models.
你知道吗  上将?
Did you know that? Admiral...
他们是有意如此编程的
They were deliberately programmed that way.
赛昂人不想让他们变得有自我意识并会抗命
The Cylons didn't want them becoming self-aware and suddenly resisting orders.
他们可不想他们自己的机器起来造反
They didn't want their own robotic rebellion on their hands.
你可以欣赏这个讽刺
You can appreciate the irony.
爸
Dad...
我知道你的意思
I know what you're saying,
但我们要对我们所留下的人负责
but we have a responsibility to the people that we left behind.
记得罗丝琳说过的
Remember what Roslin said.
我们的首要责任是让人类种族生存下去
"Our first responsibility is to the survival of humanity. "
我们不能无视这一点
We can't lose sight of that.
自从这一年来
Over the last year,
我们已经无视了很多事情
we've lost sight of almost everything.
我们变得...软弱
We got soft.
如果我们现在回去新卡布里卡 我们就输了
But if we go back to New Caprica now, and we lose,
全没了
it's over.
人类种族完蛋了
Humanity just stops
上将服上的星星没有给你做这样赌博的权力
and an admiral's stars don't give you the right to make that gamble.
你是对的  儿子
You're right, Son.
你应该制定一些恢复搜寻地球的计划
You should make plans for resuming the search for Earth
利用帕伽索斯与平民船只的资源
with Pegasus and the civilian fleet.
帕伽索斯?那卡拉狄加怎么办?
With Pegasus? What about Galactica?
我知道我们为何会留下那些人
I know why we left those people behind.
我知道去那里是他们的选择
And I know that it was their choice in the first place to be down there,
同时  我意识到人类生存下来的重要性高于一切
and I realize that the survival of the human race outweighs anything else.
但这次...
But this time,
我无法继续这样认为 无法面对它
I can't live with it, can't face it.
也许我是懦夫 但我会回来的
Maybe I'm a coward, but I'm going back...
父亲  你没有机会
Dad, you won't have a chance.
我会回来的  儿子
I'm going back, Son.
我让你的卵子受精
LEOBEN: Once I fertilized your egg,
放到一个人类女性体内 让她完成后面的步骤
we transferred it to a human woman who carried it to term.
她相当有趣
She's pretty, funny,
灿烂的笑容
great smile.
你会喜欢她的
You would have liked her.
虽然怀她的母亲死于难产 凯西的心从未动摇过
Although her mother died during childbirth, Kacey's heart never failed.
我猜她希望与你生活在一起
I guess she gets that will to live from you.
我已看到了她的未来
I've seen her path.
虽然艰难  但一切都值得
It's difficult but rewarding.
她将在一生中了解上帝的意志
She'll know the mind of God in this lifetime.
她能看到别人看不到的东西
She'll see patterns that others do not see.
她也许是从我这里得到如此纯洁的精神
She probably gets that spiritual clarity from me.
她很快就会感到饥饿 桌上有食物
She'll be hungry soon. There's food on the table.
你不会让你自己的小孩饿死  对吧
You wouldn't let your own child starve, would you?
这不是我的小孩 我甚至不知道它是不是一个人类
It's not my child. I don't even know if it's human.
半人类 而且你知道她是你的孩子 只是你不愿意承认
Half human. I mean, you know that she's yours. You just won't admit it.
该死的你准备去哪?
Where the frak are you going?
把这玩意带走
Take this with you!
别把这玩意拉下了
Hey! Don't leave me alone with this!
妈的
Frak.
我不知道你是谁或你是什么 但我知道我不是你妈妈
I don't know who or what you are, but I do know this. I'm not your mother.
我也不关心这是否有用 我也不关心赛昂人是否会停止
I don't care that it's effective. I don't care that the Cylons can't stop it.
这是个错误
It's wrong.
不要再有自杀式炸弹  上校 你明白吗?
No more suicide bombings, Colonel. You understand?
你现在为赛昂人工作吗?
What, are you working for the Cylons now?
抱歉  我不应该打你
I'm sorry. There was no excuse for that.
你看到了吧  类似这样的小事 他们已经不再在乎了
You see, little things like that, they don't matter anymore.
事实上  没有他妈的东西他们会在乎了
In fact, not too frakking much really matters anymore.
我已经在这里找到了工作  女士 也是唯一的工作
I've got one job here, lady, and one job only,
就是瓦解赛昂人
to destruct the Cylons,
让他们对任他们摆布的蝼蚁感到恐惧
make them worry about the anthill they've stirred up down here,
他们会转移注意力 当老头子回来时 会躲过他们的视线
so they're distracted and out of position when the old man shows up in orbit.
炸弹攻击已经引起了赛昂人的注意
The bombings? They got the Cylons' attention.
它们真的引起了他们的注意 而且我不会放弃的
They really got their attention. And I am not giving that up.
我们在谈论的是那些把自己炸成碎片的人们
ROSLIN: We are talking about people blowing themselves up.
你要知道  某些时候  我觉得你的血管里都是些冷水
You know, sometimes I think that you've got ice water in those veins
而另外一些时候 你又只是个天真的学校老师
and other times I think you're just a naive, little schoolteacher.
我已经在两次战争里将人送去进行自杀式任务
I've sent men on suicide missions in two wars now,
同时  也让我告诉你
and let me tell you something,
让他们驾驶着蝮蛇战机与
it don't make a gods-damn bit of difference
让他们走进检阅队伍 这两点并没有什么他妈的不同
whether they're riding in a Viper or walking out onto a parade ground.
最后  他们都只是死而已
In the end, they're just as dead.
因此请收起你的说教和你高尚的教条吧
So take your piety and your moralizing and your high-minded principles
带他们待在安全的地方直到这场战争结束
and stick them someplace safe until you're off this rock
以便能够再次坐回到你殖民地一号那张漂亮的凳子上去
and you're sitting in your nice, cushy chair on Colonial One again.
我还有一场仗要打
I've got a war to fight.
走起来  快走
MAN 1: Let's go. Move it.
往这边走  后面跟上
This way. Offload the rest.
从这里分开  走另一边
MAN 2: Let's go to isolation. Move!
拘留已经引起了不少怨声 招来了更多的敌人
BOOMER: The detentions are just causing more resentment and more enemies.
我们正在失去地面上人们的民心    快走
We're losing ground with the people. MAN 3: Let's move! Get going!
我知道 我们别无选择
I know. We don't have another option.
我们必须告诉大家自杀式炸弹袭击是不能容忍的
We have to send the message that suicide bombings won't be tolerated.
抱歉  长官  我能和你谈几句吗?
Excuse me, sir. Can I talk to you for a moment?
当然可以  杰米 我会跟上你的
Yeah, sure, Jammer. We'll catch up later.
好
Okay.
我不知道应该如何开始说
Sir, I don't know exactly how to broach this,
我也不知道我要期望你做什么 但…
nor do I know exactly what I expect you to do about it, but since we were...
自从我们从卡拉狄加下来
Anyway, since we were back on Galactica...
行了  杰米  就直说吧
Yeah, Jammer, just spit it out.
我们在最后一次围捕行动中逮捕了泰罗尔军士长的妻子凯莉
We picked up Chief Tyrol's wife on the last raid. Cally.
她在拘留所里  我认为她在名单上
She's in detention. I think she's on the list.
妈的!
Frak!
凯西?
Kacey?
卡拉?
LEOBEN: Kara?
嗨  凯莉  是我  布玛尔
Hi, Cally. It's me. Boomer.
我希望我能有把枪
I wish I had a gun.
你还好吗?我意思是你的身体
Are you all right? Physically, I mean.
你想从我这里得到什么?
What do you want from me?
听着  每个人身上都发生了很多事情
Look, a lot's happened in everyone's life.
但我想你知道  我想让你和格伦知道
But I want you to know... I want you and Galen to know
我为你们高兴
that I'm happy for you,
尤其是你们组成了一个家庭
especially since you started a family.
这些都是我和他以前的梦想
Something that him and I talked about once before.
你能帮我离开这里吗?
Can you get me out of here?
我不知道  我对内部安全事务一无所知…
I don't know. I have nothing to do with internal security...
那么去死吧  莎伦  你这个愚蠢的该死的魔鬼
Then frak you, Sharon, you stupid, frakked-up toaster.
多少次我都想射死你
How many times do I have to shoot you, anyway?
如果你帮不到我  那就快滚
If you can't help me, then just go away and leave us alone!
所有人类准备出示身份
MAN ON PA: All human personnel prepare to present identification
在通过安全扫描前
before passing through security scanners.
出示你的ID
MAN 1: Have your IDs out.
继续    所有人都准备好自己的工作ID
Keep coming, keep coming... MAN 2: Everyone have both your IDs ready.
快走 有ID的出去
Step on up. Worker IDs out.
朝前走 你! 打开你的包
Straight ahead, move it. Hey, you! Open your bag! Open your bag!
截下她
Stop her!
23个赛昂人严重损坏  14个被迫销毁
Twenty-three Cylons critically wounded. Fourteen had to be euthanized.
他们也有伤亡  4个人类死了
They had casualties, too. Four human dead.
他妈是谁干的这事?  注意你的语言
Who gives a frak about that? Pardon my language.
变电站没了
The power substation is crippled.
半个城市没有电力供应
Almost half the city is without power
最乐观估计也要两周才能修好
and our best estimates put the repairs at two weeks.
你仍然觉得我们对人类过于苛刻了吗?
You still think we're being too hard on the human population?
我们面对的是一个非常严重  非常直接的问题
We have a very serious, very straightforward problem.
我们是要加强控制或是失去控制  这是事实
Either we increase control or we lose control. That's a fact.
我们觉得是使用更强硬手段的时候了
We think it's time for stronger measures.
我们同意
We agree.
我们也同意  你们呢?
We agree as well. How about you?
我们也同意
We agree also.
总之  我们大部分都同意
Most of us do, anyway.
那就够了
Enough.
这是什么?
What's this?
这是对所有列在后页上的拘留者
This orders the summary executions
执行处刑的命令
of all the detainees listed on the next page.
需要你签名
It requires your signature.
我的签名?
My signature?
你是总统
You're the President.
迟些再看  现在就签
Read it later. Sign now.
只因为你决定这样做
Just because you've decided to do this
并不意味着你需要把他拖进你的罪恶中
doesn't mean you need to drag him into sin with you.
别向我说教
Don't you lecture me about sin.
我不是那个开创…
I'm not the one who committed the first act
赛昂人杀赛昂人历史的那个人
of Cylon-on-Cylon violence in our history.
她在说些什么?
What's she talking about?
她在卡布里卡上用一块石头把我的脑袋砸爆了
She crushed my head in with a rock back on Caprica.
真有趣  她没告诉你
Interesting she didn't tell you.
有些事我不得不做  我并不以此为荣
It was something I had to do. I'm not proud of it.
这些都很有意思  非常有教育意义  签署这份命令
This is all very interesting, very edifying. Sign the order.
你们不需要我的签名
You don't need my signature.
嗯  事实上  我们需要
D'ANNA: Well, actually, we do.
我们是殖民地合法政府的同盟与朋友
We're here as allies and friends of the legitimate government of the Colonies.
你是总统  于是我们做的所有事情都需要你的签名
You are the President, so everything we do requires your signature.
换句话说  他们是在害怕
In other words, they're worried about what God might think
上帝会认为他们是在谋杀 他们在掩盖事实
if they commit murder. They're covering their existential asses.
我不会签的
I won't do it, all right? I won't do it.
你们还是用其他方法安抚你们的良心吧
You're going to have to solve your consciences some other way.
那我们只有换一个总统了
Then we'll find another president.
住手
Stop this!
这太疯狂了
This is crazy!
上帝呀 她会回来的
Dear God. She'll be back.
但是如果他向你按下扳机  你却不会回来
But if he pulls that trigger now, you won't.
快签字
Sign it!
签字! 签上你的名字!快签!
Sign it! Sign your name! Sign it!
签字
Sign it! Sign it!
你对此无能为力  盖尤斯
CAPRICA SIX: There's nothing you can do, Gaius.
在这页纸上签字 会没事的
DORAL: Sign your name on that paper! It'll be okay.
是你
It's you.
帮帮我
Help me.
你必须签名  如果不签  他们会杀了你的
You have to sign it. They'll kill you if you don't.
签名!签名!签名!签上名字!签名!
Sign it! Sign! Sign! Sign your name! Sign it!
我办不到  我不会签的
I can't. I won't.
你不能强迫...
You can't force...
有时你必须做不想干的事 那样才能生存下来 为了将来的战斗
Sometimes you have to do things you hate, so you can survive to fight another day.
举起你的右手  重复我的话
Raise your right hand and repeat after me.
我  莎伦・阿格森
I, Sharon Agathon...
现在以我的信念与忠诚发誓
...do now pledge my faith and my loyalty...
保护科波的十二个殖民地
...to the protection of the 12 Colonies of Kobol...
并执行上级的命令
...and will carry out the lawful orders of my superiors...
成为殖民舰队的
...as an officer...
一名军官
...in the Colonial Fleet.
祝贺你  少尉
Congratulations, Lieutenant.
真没想到我能活着看到这一天
I never thought I'd live to see the day.
我也是
Me, neither.
这是件好事 是你应得的
It looks good on you. It belongs on you.
这身制服对我来说意味着很多   莎伦
This uniform, it means a lot to me, Sharon.
我知道  西洛
I know it does, Helo.
对我来说也意味着很多
It means a lot to me, too.
我不会让它蒙羞
I won't betray it.
战机检查完毕 少尉
MAN: The bird checks out, Lieutenant.
谢谢
Thanks.
我能问你个问题吗? 你怎么知道的?
Can I ask you a question? How do you know?
我是说  你怎么知道你真的能信任我?
I mean, how do you really know that you can trust me?
我不知道
I don't.
但这就是信任
That's what trust is.
祝好运  少尉
Good hunting, Lieutenant.
嘿  还真有这事
That was really something.
原以为你会喜欢
I thought you might like that.
这回你没和我玩花样
But you... You didn't do the twist this time.
你们所说的… 你最后做的那个
What do you call... What's that deal you did right at the end?
你们称之什么来着?
What do you call that?
你说的是"旋动"
You mean the swirl?
旋动
Oh, the swirl.
哎哟  还真有这事
Boy, that's really something.
你说你想要一些难忘的东西
Well, you said you wanted something memorable.
少怎样了?
How is Saul?
很好
Fine.
他什么时候和起义者进行下一次会面
And when is his next meeting with the insurgents?
别否认这事 艾伦 我们知道他是他们的领导人
No point in denying it, Ellen. We know he's their leader.
你认为我们为什么会放他出去?
Why do you think we let him out of detention?
我想是因为那次做爱
I thought it was because of the twist.
是的  肯定是
Well, yes, that too, for sure.
但是放上校出去也能使抵抗活跃起来
But having the Colonel out and active with the resistance
提供给我们某些好处
presents us with certain advantages.
我不知道任何事情
I don't know anything about...
你的否定就能说明一些事  不是吗?
Let's just consider your denials as read, shall we?
我需要具体的地点 具体的时间
I want a specific place, I want a specific time
造反领导们的一次高级会议
for a very high-level meeting of the insurgency leadership.
如果我们没有得到的话  我们会接少回来
And if I don't get it, we pick up Saul again,
而这次  他失去的就不止是一只眼睛
and this time, he'll lose more than an eye.
明天  卡拉狄加会派出两架猛禽  几名海军陆战队士兵
Tomorrow, the Galactica is going to send two Raptors, several Marines
地面联络官员将要向我们作简要介绍
and a ground liaison officer is gonna help brief us on the rescue mission
并协调我们的营救任务
and help coordinate our evac plans.
该死  真的干了 谁是联络官员
I'll be damned. It's really happening. Who is the liaison officer?
莎伦
Sharon.
我希望这是你开的玩笑
I hope that's your idea of a joke.
阿达玛上将给了她制服和官职
Admiral Adama has given her a uniform and a billet.
她是一名服役军官了 我们没什么好说的
She is a serving officer, which is more than you can say
从技术上讲
about us, technically speaking.
老头子已经失去理智了  好吧
The old man's lost his mind all right.
集合地在哪?
Where's the rendezvous?
他们让我们决定
They left that up to us.
好吧  我的建议是
Okay, here's my suggestion.
如果他们跳跃到南部Breeder峡谷以外…
If they jump into Breeder's Canyon, out here in the southern range...
进来
Come.
嗨  小家伙们    嗨  艾伦
Hey, guys. Hey, Ellen.
像我刚才说的 如果他们跳到这里
Anyway, like I was saying, if they jump in here,
就不会被赛昂的雷达发现
they won't get picked up on Cylon dradis.
这有一段距离 要走很远的路
That's a long way out there, a lot of ground to cover by foot.
我知道 我们会在半路遇到他们  大概在这
SAM: I realize that. I'm gonna meet them halfway, right about here.
从空中很难发现我们 相当隐蔽
Now, there's good cover from the air, it's pretty isolated.
我们相信这点
I've gotta be sure.
这是我们举行的最重要的会议
It may be the most important meeting we're ever gonna have.
上校  我确定就是这里
Colonel, I'm sure. This is the place.
赛昂人在这里不会发现他们
The Cylons will not find them here.
好  给我地图
All right, give me the map.
记下这些信息了吗?
Have you got the message memorized?
所有无线电频率
All the wireless freqs?
好的  也给我一份
All right, then give me the message, too.
我来吧  少  别起来
I'll do that, Saul. Don't get up.
谢谢
Thanks.
上校  我已经召集了一只6到8人的队伍
SAM: Colonel, I've assembled a team of about six to eight.
我们出去过好几次了
We've been out about half a dozen times.
如果需要的话  我们会带上一两天的食物
We have got provisions for a couple of days if we need them.
我们穿过河流
We have access to running water.
我对这一带了如指掌 会成功的
I know that place like the back of my hand. This is gonna work.
盖尤斯! 盖尤斯!
Gaius! Gaius!
你在这上面签了字?
Did you sign this?
告诉我你没签  盖尤斯!    不是现在  盖塔先生
Tell me you didn't sign this, Gaius. Not now, Mr. Gaeta.
我非常疲倦    这是份处决书
I'm very tired. This is a death warrant!
你看过上面的名字吗?
Have you seen the names on this list?
你知道他们要做什么吗?
Do you have any idea what they're about to do out there?
你听见我说话了吗?
Are you listening to me?
我没有任何选择余地
I didn't have any choice.
你到底怎么了? 在这个目录上有200多人
What the hell's the matter with you? There are over 200 names on this list.
你看过这些名字了吗?
Have you even looked at the names?
看看这些名字  盖尤斯    我已经看过了
Look at the names, Gaius! I've seen them!
我已经看过了  行了吗?
I've seen them, all right?
我无能为力
There was nothing I could do.
出发
MAN: Let's go!
快 快 快
Move! Move! Move! Move! Move!
你还要乘3倍  你能做到的 让我看下…
And you do triple digits. You can do that. Let me see.
劳拉・罗丝琳 请跟我们走一趟
Laura Roslin? Come with us, please.
杀死泰罗尔的妻子只会使他反抗地更强烈
Killing Tyrol's wife will only embitter him against us.
他是工会主席
He's the head of a labor union, an organized faction...
拜托  莎伦.我们实话实说好了
Come on, Sharon, let's just be honest with one another.
其实在你看来  你不会考虑杀掉他们中的任何一个
In your view, you don't think there's any reason to kill anyone.
对吧?    是的
Correct? Right.
我们做出的这个决定  我们所有人
Well, we made a decision, all of us,
就像我们刚到这里时
just like when we listened to you and Caprica Six
你和卡布里卡6号说的那样
when we came here to start this new and glorious chapter
掀开赛昂人与人类光辉的新篇章
in Cylon-human relations.
我们处决凯莉根本起不了什么作用
This has nothing to do with whether or not we execute Cally.
没人喜欢这个主意  布玛尔
No one enjoys the thought of mortal death, Boomer.
但她试图杀死你 也许这就是上帝的公正吧
But she tried to murder you. Maybe it's Gods' justice.
需要扶梯吗  副总统先生?
Need a lift, Mr. Vice President?
我想是的
I guess so.
最近没怎么看到你 很忙吗?
I haven't seen much of you lately. Been busy these days, huh?
还好  拘留室里没什么事可做
Well, not much to do in detention.
你被关了多久了?
How long have you been held?
我想大概四个月吧
Four months, I think.
我告诉过波塔尔我是不会与赛昂人合作的
I told Baltar I wouldn't have any part of collaborating with the Cylons,
然后他就愤怒了
and he got a little pissed.
他对我也有点不满
He's a little pissed at me, too.
跳跃完成 到达目标上方   好的 保持联系 伙计们
Jump complete. Right on target. Okay, hang on, guys.
我正下降到指定着陆点
We're dropping down to the landing point,
在前方有强干扰
and there's some heavy turbulence up ahead.
沿着河走 一定要贴近河岸
Follow the river. Make sure you hug the bank.
是 长官
MAN: Yes, sir.
好了  一旦我们到达指定地点 守在后面  并提供掩护
ATHENA: Okay, once we reach the rendezvous point, stay back and provide cover.
走吧
ATHENA: Go Panthers!
CBucks规则!
C- Bucks rule!
嗨  萨姆  好久不见
Hey, Sam, been a long time.
真有趣  我觉得每天都看见你似的
Funny, I... I feel like I see you every day.
来吧  我们走
Come on.
上帝啊  请别带走她
Lords, please don't take her life.
那是我的过错  不要惩罚她
It was my mistake. Don't punish her for it.
只是一次事故  卡拉  没什么了
It was an accident, Kara, nothing more.
凯西?
Kacey.
凯西  噢  我的天  宝贝
Kacey. Oh, my Gods. Honey.
让他们伸伸手脚吧
Let them stretch their legs for a minute.
是  长官
Yes, sir!
我们走  好了  所有人出来
Let's go! All right, everybody out!
5分钟休息  快点!  都出来
Five minute rest break! Come on, move! Everybody out!
5分钟休息  出发
Five minute rest break, max! Let's go!
来吧  5分钟  所有人出来
Come on, five minutes. Everyone out! Let's go!
告诉我事实  劳拉
Tell me something, Laura.
就在前面
MAN: Right up front!
去年那次 你想要窃取选举 是吗
Last year, you tried to steal an election, didn't you?
是的  我是这么做的  汤姆
Yes, I did, Tom.
真希望你当时能成功
I wish you'd gone through with it.
我也是
Me, too.
我们会等到黄昏才返回城市里去
SAM: We'll wait until nightfall before we go back to the city.
这里有一些下水道我们以前用过...
There's a system of tunnels we've been using. Our levels under...
嘘  你们听到了吗?
You hear that?
隐蔽
ATHENA: Down! Get down!
快 掩护
SAM: Move, take cover!
快!
Go, go, go!
你  过来这里
You, over here.
快跑 别回头 走
Run. Run, don't look back. Go!
快走
Let's go.